Our brains may be operating as analog
computers, and it may have some pretty
interesting implications for robotics.
Yes, researchers out of MIT have
proposed that our brains are actually
using analog functions in order to
compute.
This is a fairly interesting area
because neuroscientists will often say
that our brains are not simply computers
and we cannot treat them as such. And
yet, we keep finding evidence that they
operate very much like a computer. Now,
in order to understand this, we have to
understand computers a little bit. The
ones that we're mostly familiar with are
digital, so they have zero and one, on
and off. But, there's also analog
computers, and those ones have waves.
That means that they have a continuous
state for which they can use to compute.
And our brains were thought to work like
a digital computer for a long time. We
have neurons, those neurons communicate
with each other. However, each
individual neuron can take on multiple
jobs in different states.
We also believed that brain waves, you
know, the waves that we get from an EEG,
they can help determine things like
consciousness, if somebody's in a coma.
We thought that those were just a
byproduct, they didn't have any meaning,
but more evidence is showing up that
brain waves are actually involved in the
computation itself. That means that that
brain wave has a field for which it can
influence the neurons themselves. This
would also have a lot of applications
for medicine because it would mean that
we can replicate brain waves in order to
help treat things like depression, and
some things like that are already done.
But, one of the really interesting
things for me is that these processes
were already utilized in computation
when it comes to physical reservoir
computers. That's where the intelligence
of a robot or AI comes from the physical
properties of the system itself, and
that includes waves.
Computing with the physical properties
of the system. Yes, that would make a
lot of sense for our brains and a lot of
sense for robotics, and it's one of the
things that I really enjoy when humans
find the right answer, but after doing
everything the hard way.
AI, while it is useful for a great
number of things, is also
extraordinarily power-hungry. So, the
pursuit of neuromorphic computation has
been to try to make something that is,
you know, a little bit more
environmentally friendly. But, we're
also making something that acts and
looks very much like our brains. I think
it is worthy to say that biology had
billions of years to get to this point.
It figured out a computation system that
works. So, why not borrow it or
plagiarize it? I don't think we're going
to make something better than nature has
already figured out, to be perfectly
honest. So, in the pursuit of not having
to make something better, a lot of
biology has been incorporated into
robotics. Not just trying to make
something that looks like biology, but
actual physical cells. Biohybrids
interest me a great deal. And one of the
surprising things for me is that with
digital computers, biological components
are perfectly happy to play. They aren't
incompatible.
We can give robots something very close
to human vision, or we can just culture
our own retinas and use that to process
vision for a robot. In a more recent
paper, the cells used to smell were
incorporated into a robot. So, they
basically gave it a nose. And yes, it
worked. They were able to differentiate
between different smells like lemons or
flowers. Some of the research that
people find most disturbing has come out
of Japan. Like the smiling flesh thing.
And I actually really like it just
because it's creepy. This is the idea
that you could give a robot a living
skin using human tissues. And they've
also taken that farther. You can give
robots muscle tissues. These are going
to be self-healing. And they're also
biodegradable.
This research group made an entirely
biodegradable robot, including the
electrical components. Things that are
compatible with degrading. So, our
bodies do not last forever. And
eventually, they are returned to the
earth. But, we can do the same for
robots. We can give robots a lifespan.
And these can be incorporated with
living components, or we can just have
biodegradable components that are not
living. I came across this one again,
and I just love showing it to people.
It's a proof of principle, a model for
how you could make as living a robot as
possible, and they made the dog
quadruped flesh thing.
Human skin, a digestive system, and eats
sugar water, but these are becoming
increasingly possible. Researchers have
made robots with each individual
component. They just have not all been
combined. This raises the question for
me,
at what point have we just made an
animal? Because yeah, you can make
robots with human tissues. You can give
them little human brains, and they
aren't a human, right? They weren't
born.
But at some point, I think if we
continue down this path, we will end up
with replicants.
This area of science tends to be some of
the most disturbing that people will
learn about, and I do understand why.
Because we're taking things that are so
close to what it means to be alive and
giving it to a creation. And we've had
stories about that forever.
Even prior to robotics, we've had
stories in human history about making
people from clay and wood and coming
alive, and that was always a cautionary
tale. So, I do understand why we might
find similarities in some of the things
that research is doing now.
A big part of me really wants to know if
we can create something that is
conscious, or if consciousness has to
look like our brain in order to exist.
There's lots of creatures out there that
do not have a nervous system like our
own, and they're still alive. They're
still capable of cognition. Go ask slime
molds and fungi.
A lot of the time with my content,
people ask me why. Why are we doing
this? And I could give you the answer
that the grant proposal probably
included, including biomedical and
industrial applications, or I can tell
you because we can. I
think this research is done simply
because we can.
Either way, I will keep you up to date.
In fact, you really don't have a choice.
Follow for more.
>> normal structures. Are you carrying on
tiny cells